亚瑟!
Arthur!
快进来
Come inside at once!
你没长耳朵么?
Can't you hear me calling?
- 你在吃什么? - 嘘 嘘
- What are you eating? - Shh,shh.
嘘 你会吵醒她的
Shh,you'll wake her.
天啊!
Dear God!
敌暗我明
费雪小姐探案集
我又找到一件衣服 小姐
I've found another costume,Miss,
但得好好熨一下才能打包
but they'll all need a good airing before we pack them.
别担心 桃乐西 离舞会还有几天呢
Don't worry,Dot. We have a couple of days left before the ball.
已经有了罗马武士服 小丑服
So that's a Roman warrior,a clown,
小红帽披肩 狼皮装 和天使装
a Little Red Riding Hood,the Wolf,an angel
还有埃及艳后要分开装
and I'll pack Cleopatra separately
- 那样就不会皱了 - 非常好
- so the frock won't crush. - Wonderful.
我最爱化妆舞会了
There's nothing I like better than a fancy dress ball,
但把订婚舞会搞成这样确实有些奇怪
although it does seem an odd choice for an engagement party.
普璐登斯姨妈居然没对此提出异议
I am surprised your Aunt Prudence doesn't think it unseemly,Miss.
她肯定心有不满
I'm sure she does.
但我亲爱的表兄总能
But my darling cousin Guy has always found a way
把她哄得团团转
to wrap the old dear around his little pinkie.
巴特勒先生 今天的车不会出什么故障吧?
Mr Butler,any chance of a broken fan belt or a flat tyre today?
绝不可能 小姐
No chance at all,Miss.
您的车会快得像在做梦
Your motor car is running like a dream.
我来接
I'll get it.
您好 我是费雪
Hello,Miss Fisher speaking.
普璐登斯姨妈... 午餐取消了?
Aunt Prudence... Luncheon's off?
真可惜
What a shame.
哦 不是吧
Oh,no.
当然没问题 你报警了吗?
Yes,of course. Did you call the police?
那我来报吧
Leave it to me.
请为我转接城南警察局
Connect me to City South Police Station,please.
杰克・罗宾逊探长 紧急事件
Detective Jack Robinson. It's urgent.
把你的帽子别紧 桃乐西 咱们要飞驰了
Put another pin in your hat,Dot. You're in for a very fast ride.
芙莱妮 这绝对是场灾难
Phryne,this is a complete disaster!
这可怜的姑娘
The poor,unfortunate girl.
居然在舞会前两天遭遇不测
Two days before the engagement party.
别担心 妈妈
Don't worry,Mother.
舞会肯定会照常进行的
There can be no question of the party going ahead.
- 你好 盖伊 - 芙莱妮表妹
- Hello,Guy. - Cousin Phryne.
不好意思 我身上有点湿
Excuse me,I'm a little damp.
咱们相见本应该在愉快的场合
It was supposed to be a happy occasion when we met again.
这位是我的闺蜜 桃乐西 威廉姆斯女士
May I present my companion,Miss Dorothy Williams.
这是盖伊・斯坦利先生
Mr Guy Stanley.
威廉姆斯小姐 幸会
Miss Williams,pleasure.
- 死者是谁? - 玛丽古德・布朗
- So who is she? - Marigold Brown.
她是马夫的女儿 我雇了她做侍女
She's the stablehand's daughter. I engaged her as chambermaid.
我 我想我们该等警察来
I-I think we should wait for the police to arrive.
芙莱妮! 别动她
Phryne! Don't touch her.
真漂亮
Pretty girl.
警察来了 小姐
Inspector's coming,Miss.
你来得也太是时候了吧
You made it here in alarmingly good time.
我走的小路
I know a shortcut.
在哪儿发现她的?
Where was she found?
她浮在泳池中央
Floating in the middle of the swimming pool.
我九点左右从这条路上走过 去拿玫瑰
I walked this way at about nine o'clock for the roses
但当时并没看见什么可疑之处
but I saw nothing suspicious then.
谁把她拉出水面的? 我儿子 盖伊
Who pulled her out of the water? My son,Guy.
那是十点之后的事了
It was after ten o'clock.
我还妄想她可能活着
I had a mad hope she might still be alive.
看起来她伤到了头
Looks like she hit her head.
可能在泳池边摔的
Perhaps on the edge of the pool.
真是不幸
Such a tragic mishap.
来 妈妈
Come,Mother.
说吧 你是怎么想的?
Well,come on. What's your theory?
看她的衣领周围
Take a look around her collar.
这孩子不是淹死的 是被勒死的
This girl didn't drown. She was strangled.
被谋杀的? 可怜的姑娘
Murdered?! The poor,poor girl.
最后一次看见她是在什么时候? 今早么?
When was she last seen? Did anyone spot her this morning?
我得问问管家特露布尼夫人
I'll have to ask my housekeeper,Mrs Truebody.
芙莱妮 请帮我摇下铃吧?
Phryne,would you ring the bell,please?
我叫你待在房里的
I told you to stay in your room.
我想和玛丽古德玩嘛
I want to play with Marigold.
她去哪儿啦?
W-Where is she?
她睡着了 我亲爱的孩子
She's sleeping,my darling boy.
啊 看谁来了
Ah,look who's just arrived.
芙莱妮表妹
Cousin Phryne.
看我给你带什么来了
And look what I have for you.
棒棒糖
Gobstoppers.
超大哦!
They're enormous!
你乖乖回房 才能给你
You can't have them unless you go back to your room.
正如你所见 探长先生 我儿子他...
As you see,Detective Inspector,my son is...
他智商有缺陷
Well,his faculties are limited.
照例我们还是要问过这家的每一个成员
We'll need to speak to every member of the household all the same.
- 包括亚瑟 - 当然
- Including Arthur. - Of course.
我们去哪找这女孩的爸爸?
The girl's father. Where can we find him?
赫尔伯特・布朗? 他住在马房后面的小屋
Herbert Brown? He lodges behind the stable house.
噢 天杀的特露布尼去哪儿了?
Oh,where in heaven's name is Mrs Truebody?
她才十六岁 还是个小女孩
She was only 16. Still a little girl.
她母亲过世后 我尽全力照顾她
I've done my best since we lost her mother.
谢天谢地 她妈不用承受这噩耗
Thank God she's not here for this.
你最后一次见到你的女儿是什么时候?
When was the last time you saw your daughter?
应该是昨晚
That would have been last night.
睡觉之前吧 玛丽古德喜欢临睡前看我一眼
About bedtime. Marigold likes to check on me of an evening.
但今早你没见过她?
But you didn't see her this morning?
她当上女佣后
She stays up at the servant quarters in the main house
住在主楼的佣人卧室
since they put her on as a maid.
她适应的很好
She was coming up in the world.
恐怕按照惯例 我得问问
I'm afraid I have to ask where you were this morning.
你今早九到十点在哪
Just for the record,between nine and ten o'clock.
跟往常一样 我在...清除马粪
Where I always am...mucking out the stables.
这有人能为您作证吗?
Can anyone confirm this for us? Anyone here?
是的 盖伊先生
Yes. Mr Guy.
他过来看这些马
He came over to look at the horses.
噢 是的 他还让我帮他
Oh,that's right. He asked me to saddle up
备了几个鞍
a couple of mounts for him.
他和一个女性朋友
Him and his lady friend.
我同我
I had breakfast
迷人的未婚妻伊莎贝拉
with my ravishing bride-to-be,
在房间里吃早饭
Isabella,in my room.
几点钟?
What time was that?
很早 应该是九点
Early,must have been nine.
那是破晓时分喽
Practically the crack of dawn.
- 之后呢? - 跟往常一样
- What'd you do after that? - The usual.
下楼 拿张报纸
Just came downstairs,nabbed the newspaper,
在花园闲逛
wafted about the garden.
- 是马房附近吗? - 是的 的确如此
- Anywhere near the stables? - Yes,actually.
既然你提起 我是去看老马了
Now you mention it,I went to see my old horses.
当时是几点?
What time would that have been?
这...我没事
Ah,I've never really been
天天看表干嘛
a watch-the-clock type of fellow.
- 还有别人在吗? - 只有赫伯特
- Was anyone else there? - Just Herbert.
家母趁邻居
Mother inherited him
缺钱买跑车的时候雇佣了他
when the neighbour sold off their nags for sports cars.
我的意思是 他的确对马匹很在行
I mean... I mean,he does know his horseflesh,though.
天啊 你们不会以为
Oh,surely you don't think he had anything to do
他与他女儿的死有关吧?
with his daughter's death?
审问过家中其他人以后
We're just eliminating him from our enquiries
我才能排除他的嫌疑
as we'll be doing with the rest of the household.
何时方便能和你未婚妻聊聊?
Tell me,when might we speak with your fiance?
伊莎贝拉. 我是芙莱妮・费雪.
Isabella. Phryne Fisher.
啊! 是表妹
Ah! The cousin.
我们见过是吧? 在查灵克罗斯酒店的舞会上
We've met,haven't we? That dazzling party in Charing Cross.
那天盖伊还朗诵了
Guy ended up on the dining table
下流版本的"燃烧甲板上的男孩"
reciting an indecent version of The Boy Stood On The Burning Deck.
啊 是呀!
Ah,yes!
亲爱的 芙莱妮让我想起了我们相爱的那晚
Darling,Phryne's just reminding me of the night we fell in love.
至少她知道要嫁的是怎样的一个浪子
At least she knows what a terrible rake she's marrying.
我认为我们俩是绝配
I think we're perfectly suited.
等你准备好 罗宾逊探长在前厅
When you're ready,Inspector Robinson's waiting for you
等你
in the front parlour.
我要打扮下不? 他长得帅不?
Should I dress,or not? How good-looking is he?
芙莱妮 很抱歉上不了茶水
Phryne,I'm sorry I can't offer you tea.
我刚听说我的管家黎明时分就离开了
I've just been told my housekeeper left at dawn.
警察可不会喜欢听到这消息
The police won't be happy about that.
我们来以后 都走了两个了
That's the second one since we arrived.
你怎么对待你的仆人的 斯坦利夫人?
What do you do to your staff,Mrs Stanley?
特露布尼无缘无故地就走人了?
Mrs Truebody just upped and left without any reason?
你的姨妈不过是批评她做的奶油松饼
Apart from your aunt telling her the croquembouche tower
看起来像有人在里面扎了根针一样
looked like someone stuck a pin in it.
今天真是个坏日子
This is turning out to be such a beastly day.
你应该知道我们不得不取消舞会吧 伊莎贝拉
You do realise we'll have to cancel the party,Isabella.
那是当然 这是澳洲人的风格嘛
Absolutely. It's so adorably Australian.
一大家子人都得为了
Where else but in the Antipodes would an entire household
一个马夫的女儿哀悼个不停
go into mourning over a stablehand's daughter,
虽然那姑娘很不错
sweet as the girl was.
对你应该无碍吧
That shouldn't bother you.
反正你的亲朋好友都是伦敦人 不是么?
Everybody who's worth knowing lives in London anyway,don't they?
是的 盖伊想说服他妈妈接受
True. It was a silly idea of Guy's
订婚仪式这事真是个蠢主意
foisting the engagement on his poor mother.
我可不蠢
It was not silly at all!
如果这场婚礼在海外举行
If the wedding is to be held overseas,
理应由我操持一切
it's perfectly reasonable I should host the engagement.
这事还有待商榷
Well,it's a moot point now.
不好意思 我和警官有约呢
Excuse me,I have a date with a policeman.
母亲 恐怕只能先这样了
It's probably all for the best,Mother.
我觉得你应该按计划行事 普璐登斯姨妈
I think you should go ahead as planned,Aunt Prudence.
- 我可以把我的佣人借你 - 此话当真?
- I'll loan you my staff. - Would you really?
我很乐意 就是不知这样是否合适
Although I'm not entirely sure it's appropriate.
这样才对得起玛丽古德
There's nothing more you can do for Marigold
和那些远道而来的英国客人嘛
and some of your guests have sailed from England.
那你手下搞的宴席是否能...
What about the catering? Would that be...?
达到你的水准?
Up to scratch?
蓝丝带厨师学校:悉尼著名厨师学校
- 巴特勒先生可是蓝丝带毕业大厨 - 噢
- Mr Butler is cordon bleu trained. - Oh!
我们还需要几个服务员和男仆
We'll need waiters and footmen.
我恰巧知道几个澳洲绅士
I know a couple of gentlemen who might fit the bill
能符合你的要求
in an antipodean kind of way.
- 你看如何? - 我看不错
- If that would help? You know,I believe it would.
谢谢你了
Thank you.
哈! 好啊各位
Ah! Hello there.
你们中的哪个想调查我
Which one of you wants to inspect me?
没有拖拉的痕迹 连点绳索碎屑都没有
No drag marks. Not so much as a snapped twig.
那我估计是有人扛着已经被勒死的她
Then I'd say somebody carried her,already strangled,
直接扔到了泳池里
and just dropped her in the pool.
赫伯特的事怎么样?
What about Herbert?
他的不在场证明和你表兄的陈述吻合了
His alibi matched up with your cousin's story.
他帮着备鞍子
He was saddling the horses
你表哥绕着房子跑了几圈
for a bit of a gallop around the estate.
你们这些上等人早上不就爱干这些么?
Isn't that what the upper class do of a morning?
也许吧 但盖伊不会
Possibly but not Guy.
他八岁的时候骑海滩上小马驹摔着了
He was kicked in the teeth by a foreshore pony at the age of eight
从此就再也不骑马科动物了
and he's refused to mount anything equine ever since.
那赫伯特为何撒谎说备鞍的事?
Why would Herbert lie about saddling the horses?
而为何盖伊会到马房附近去?
And why would Guy go anywhere near the stables in the first place?
伊莎贝拉呢? 她有什么问题么
What about Isabella? Anything worth noting?
除了她暴露穿着之外没问题
Not apart from her outfit.
这家人我们差不多问完了 是吧科林斯?
We're just about done with the household,aren't we,Collins?
- 除了那个管家 - 是的长官
- Apart from the housekeeper? - Yes,sir.
特露布尼夫人住在这所以她没有其他家庭住址
Mrs Truebody lived in so there's no home address.
但我查到了她登记求职的机构
But I have the name of the agency she was registered with.
好的 咱们回警局 然后找找这家机构
Good. Let's get back to the station. We can track it down.
那盖伊和赫伯特陈词中的不合理之处怎么办?
What about the discrepancy between Guy and Herbert's evidence?
我们在查啊
We're pursuing it.
照我看是一个漏洞百出串通好的供词
I'd say a poorly thought-out collusion.
有可能 但是现在我得去赴约了
Possibly. But right now,I'm late for another appointment.
赴谁的约?
Who's your appointment with?
大律师 估计是出席法庭之类的事
Barrister. Must be some kind of court appearance.
快走了 科林斯
Get moving,Collins!
我希望你没引进来蚂蚁
I hope no ants followed you in.
我不知道这能说明什么 是在树篱下找到的
I'm not sure what it means but I found it under the hedge
就在你为了些要紧事匆忙走后
after you rushed off for more urgent matters.
你和律师见的如何?
How did you go with your barrister?
- 什么? - 休当时说了一句
- What? - Hugh mentioned it in passing.
案子很棘手?
Tricky case coming up?
呃 我遇到的最棘手的 不过你不必担心
Um,my most challenging yet but not one that concerns you.
额头有轻微擦伤
Minor abrasion to forehead,
颈部和气管处有严重瘀伤
severe bruising to neck and windpipe,
以上为溺水前造成
inflicted prior to immersion.
最有可能的致死原因是
Most likely cause of death was asphyxiation
被勒窒息而死 都是意料之中啊
due to strangulation.' No surprises there.
继续看
Read on.
- 上背部有鞭抽伤痕? - 有人抽过她
- 'Welt marks to the upper back'? - Someone was belting her.
没有迹象表明死者曾受性侵犯
'No evidence of forced sexual penetration,
但死者非处女之身
however deceased was not a virgin.'
还有药理学报告说
And the toxicology report say
她死前的一晚喝下了
she consumed copious amounts of alcohol
大量的酒精
the night before she died.
看来没人太监护她的生活
She didn't lead a sheltered life,then.
而且如果调查再深入一点
And there could be a boyfriend we should be suspecting somewhere
我们应该能找出她的男友
if we dig a little deeper.
简 很高兴见到你 还有巴特勒先生
Jane,how nice to see you. And Mr Butler.
- 乐意效劳 斯坦利夫人 - 其他人呢?
- At your service,Mrs Stanley. - Where are the others?
赛斯和伯特马上就来
Cec and Bert were right behind us.
不是那两个前码头暴民工人吧
Not those two ex-wharfie rabble-rousers.
是你要用人的 普璐登斯姨妈
You wanted staff,Aunt Prudence.
你还有一整天训练他们上道呢
You still have a full day to get them into line.
介绍一下 阿尔伯特・强森和塞西尔・雅茨
Ah! Mr Albert Johnson and Mr Cecil Yates.
想必你们已经见过我的姨妈普璐登斯夫人了
I'm sure you've met my aunt,Mrs Prudence Stanley.
早啊
G'day.
明天一切都会顺利进行的
This'll shape up very nicely by tomorrow.
给我小心点
Do be careful!
你们一个月那点工资还买不起一瓶香槟呢!
Each bottle of that champagne is worth more than your weekly wage!
那他妈肯定是金子酒
Must be bloody liquid gold.
法国产的? 真不错
French? How heavenly.
盖伊看来搞错了
Guy seems to have made a mistake.
我订了两打酒 不是二十打
I ordered two dozen,not 20 dozen.
这么说是你付账喽 盖伊跑哪去了
I gather you are paying for it. Where is Guy,anyway?
正在给寻宝游戏想线索呢
Finishing the clues for the treasure hunt.
斯坦利夫人 说说您的真实想法?
Mrs Stanley,your honest opinion?
哦 我的苍天啊
Oh,my stars.
假发是不是太长了?
Do you think the wig is too much?
我知道你们这些年轻小姑娘比较开放
I... know you bright young things like to whoop it up a bit
但是谨记咱们的客人
but please remember some of our guests
可都是些有身份的贵客
are highly influential people.
- 伊莎贝拉这是我的养女简 - 你好啊
- Isabella,my ward,Jane. - How do you do?
这是聚会上你的服装么
Is that your costume for the party?
戈代娃夫人:伯爵夫人裸骑绕城为向丈夫请求减税
是啊 我是戈代娃夫人
Yes,I'm Lady Godiva.
我还以为你是夏娃 戈代娃没有那片叶子
I thought you were Eve. Godiva didn't have a fig leaf.
噢! 聪明女孩啊
Oh! Clever girl.
别在这弄!
Please! Not here!
简 你何不进厨房
Jane,why don't you go into the kitchen
让巴特勒先生做些茶来?
and ask Mr Butler for some tea?
小孩子最可爱了
They're so sweet at that age.
可怜的小玛丽古德 被恶棍爸爸欺凌
Poor little Marigold and that villain of a father.
真希望他能被绞死
I hope they hang him.
- 伊莎贝拉! - 不是他是谁?
- Isabella! - Who else would have done it?
- 那个老醉鬼 - 可怜的布朗先生
- He was an old soak. - Poor Mr Brown.
他果真嗜酒么?
Is he a drinker?
我不知道她在说些什么
I don't know what she's talking about.
弗雷泽爵士可对他赞誉有加 你们是在胡说!
Lord Fraser couldn't recommend him highly enough. Ridiculous!
布朗先生?
Mr Brown?
我来这的路上
I stopped in to have a word
顺便拜访了一下你姨妈的邻居
with your aunt's neighbour on the way here.
根据弗雷泽爵士所说 赫尔伯特・布朗的鞭子
According to Lord Fraser,Herbert Brown was quick to use a whip
不止在马身上打得响
and not just on his horses.
而且看来他不止
And it seems he liked more than
喝那些廉价烈酒
a drop of cheap,nasty hard liquor.
- 这酒的确不便宜 - 有何贵干?
- Doesn't look too cheap to me. - Can I help you?
布朗先生 您从哪来的这酒?
How did you come by this,Mr Brown?
酒吧买的呗
The usual way. At the pub.
这周边的烟酒商店可买不来这等好酒
You wouldn't find this at your local watering hole.
这可是世界上最昂贵的苏格兰威士忌之一
It's one of the most expensive scotch whiskeys in the world.
我可不懂这个
I didn't know that.
这是盖伊先生送我的一个礼物罢了
It was a present. Mr Guy gave it to me.
- 为何给你 - 感谢我的辛勤劳动吧
- Why? - He must appreciate my hard work.
玛丽古德有没有提到过有人虐待她?
Did Marigold mention anyone mistreating her?
或者逼她做什么?
Punishing her for anything?
据我所知没有 怎么了?
Not that I recall,why?
你女儿尸体上有鞭打的痕迹
There were welt marks on your daughter's body.
也许你把她错当成马了
Perhaps you mistook her for a horse.
我偶尔教训了她几次 那是为她好
I may have taken the belt to her once or twice for her own good.
那帮臭小子成天凑在她周围
The lads were like bees around a honey pot.
我可不想让她被搞大了肚子 我还能怎么做?
I didn't want her to get knocked up. What was I supposed to do?
你们没事就走吧 我还要干活呢
Now if you're done with me,I've got things I should do.
当然的
Of course.
他教育孩子的方法我可不太认同
He doesn't impress me with his child-rearing skills.
但我也不信他是杀人凶手
I'm not convinced he's a killer either.
有没有可能不是盖伊包庇赫伯特
What if it's not Guy covering up for Herbert Brown
而是反过来呢?
but the other way round?
那威士忌酒就能说得通了
That would explain the bottle of scotch.
啊 您在这呢 长官
Ah,there you are,sir.
呃 我联系了中介
Ah,I contacted the agency
但是在费雪小姐的姨妈之前
but Mrs Truebody hasn't been in contact
特露布尼夫人没有任何联系人
since they placed with Miss Fisher's aunt.
这么说她没有联系好下家
So she left in a hurry with no forwarding address
就匆忙离去了
and no position to move on to.
长官 你觉得她是凶手吗?
Do you think she's our killer,sir?
没准她知道些内幕
Or she knows who is.
不管怎样 我们似乎走进了死胡同
Either way,we seem to have reached a dead end.
我知道你审问过了所有职员
I know you interviewed all the staff.
但是千万别小看楼下八卦的力量
But never underestimate the power of downstairs gossip.
特露布尼夫人不可能人间蒸发了
Mrs Truebody can't have disappeared.
她去因维罗戈的度假小屋了
She was headed for a holiday cottage at Inverloch.
她每年都喜欢感受一下海风的气息
Goes there once a year to take the sea air,apparently.
那里叫什么来着?
What was that name again?
"海风"还是"海景"来着
Sea Wind. Sea View or something.
"海洋微风"
Sea Breeze.
"海洋微风度假村"
Sea Breeze Holiday Cottages.
有什么问题吗 巴特勒先生?
Any problems,Mr Butler?
没有 斯坦利夫人
No,Mrs Stanley.
一切进展顺利
Everything is going very well.
小伙 找个好地方放着
Find a safe place to store that,good chap.
那是有名的英国乳糖吗?
Is that your famous English fudge?
你肯定不会喜欢它的 妈 它是用无花果做的
Ah,you wouldn't like it,Mother. It's made with figs.
恶!
Ugh!
费雪小姐 请问这乳糖有什么特别之处?
May I ask,Miss Fisher,what is so special about this fudge?
除了产地在国外这点
Apart from the country of origin,of course.
相信我 巴特勒先生 它真的非常特别
Believe me,Mr Butler,it's very special indeed.
海洋微风度假村 在因维罗戈
Sea Breeze Holiday Cottages,Inverloch.
k... r...
Kah... rr...
m... s 屑
mm... ss. Crumbs.
面包屑! 面包屑!
Breadcrumbs! Breadcrumbs!
我在读"奇幻森林历险记"
I'm reading Hansel And Gretel.
- 我只是教他几个单词 - 礼物 是礼物
- I just taught him a few words. - It's a present. A present!
我什么时候忘了给你带礼物过?
When I do not bring you a present?
但愿你还没选礼服
Hope you haven't chosen your costume yet.
既然"奇幻森林历险记"是你最喜欢的童话
Since Hansel and Gretel is your favourite fairytale.
汉塞尔与葛雷特是小说奇幻森林历险记的两个主人公
我要当汉塞尔了 我... 我要当汉塞尔
I'm going to be Hansel. I-I'm going to be Hansel
你猜谁要当葛雷特
and,and guess who's going to be Gretel?
- 谁? - 你猜
- Who? - Guess.
玛丽古德! 她 她 她也喜欢童话
Marigold! She,she,she loves fairytales.
亲爱的... 玛丽古德已经不在这了
Darling... Marigold isn't here anymore.
- 她去哪了? - 她必须得离开
- Where is she? - She had to go away.
- 因为我吗? - 不 当然不是了
- Because of me?-  No,of course not.
肯定是 就因为我没把我的拔丝苹果给她
Yes it is. Because I didn't give her my toffee apple.
还有妈妈的缘故
A-And Mother's cross too
因为我不可以吃糖糖的
because I'm not supposed to have sweeties.
你看到过玛丽古德没有?
Tell me,did you see Marigold?
芙莱妮 够了!
Phryne! That's enough.
你为什么告诉杰克・罗宾逊
Why did you tell Jack Robinson
是你发现的玛丽古德?
it was you who found Marigold?
确实是我发现的
I did find her.
亚瑟根本不知道她死了 但愿现在也别知道
Arthur had no idea she was dead. Still doesn't,I hope.
得有人告诉他真相 他有权知道
Well,somebody should tell him. He has a right to know.
芙莱妮 小詹妮失踪至今多久了?
How long is it now since Little Janey disappeared,Phryne?
你妹妹失踪时亚瑟还是个孩子
Arthur was still a boy when your sister went missing.
他现在还会做噩梦 在半夜惊醒
He still has bad dreams,still awakes in the night,
呼唤她
calling for her.
这次情况不同 已经没有任何希望了
Well,this time there's no reason to hope.
对亚瑟来说最好莫过于告诉他真相
The kindest thing you can do for Arthur is tell him that.
- 亚瑟! - 詹妮!
- Arthur! - Janey!
亚瑟 赶快住手!
Arthur,stop it at once!
- 詹妮! - 求求你了!
- Janey! - For pity's sake!
- 詹妮 快回来! - 嘘...
- Janey,come back! - Shh...
我只是在教他我的名字而已!
I was just teaching him my name,that's all!
我只要詹妮回来
I just want Janey to come back.
他是说玛丽古德吗?
Does he mean Marigold?
那个伐木工有没有伤害玛丽古德?
Did the woodcutter hurt Marigold?
没有 你弄错了
No. You've got it wrong.
根本没有什么伐木工
There was no woodcutter.
他就在花园里 还给了她一个拔丝苹果
He was in the garden and he gave her a toffee apple.
我看见他了!
I saw him!
这儿吗?
Here?
你当时在哪?
And where were you?
藏起来了?
Hiding?
那个伐木工给你了一个苹果?
The woodcutter gave you an apple?
叫我走开
To go away.
但是我没走
But I didn't go away.
后来...
And then...
你看见伐木工和玛丽古德在一起
You saw the woodcutter with Marigold.
她没睡着 对吗?
She wasn't asleep,was she?
那个伐木工用斧子杀了她 对吗?
The woodcutter killed her with his axe,didn't he?
是的 亲爱的
Yes,dear.
我要是也有个斧子就好了
I wish I had an axe.
我就会找到他把他劈成两半
I'd go and I'd find him and I'd chop him up.
不 不要那样说话
No,don't talk like that.
亚瑟 那个人我们认识吗?
Arthur,was it someone we know?
是玛丽古德的爸爸吗?
Marigold's father?
还是房子里别的什么人?
Someone else from the house?
他长什么样? 高还是矮?
What did he look like? Tall? Short?
什么颜色的头发?
What colour hair?
不 不 就是那个伐木工 我看见过他
No,no,it was the woodcutter. I saw him.
和以前带走詹妮那人一样
The same one. The one who took Janey.
不可能
That's not possible.
詹妮失踪时是有遗留过一个拔丝苹果
There was a toffee apple left behind when Janey disappeared.
我以为是巧合就没在意
I've tried to dismiss it as coincidence.
就是巧合 默多克・福伊尔已经死在狱中了
That's all it is. Murdoch Foyle died in prison.
可如果他骗了所有人呢?
But what if he's duped us all?
他用了什么诡计 或找了替死鬼
With trickery or he paid people to help feign his death
好让我们都以为他死了
so that we all think he's gone
但是他实际却一直伺机报复
but he's just biding his time,waiting to strike.
- 报复谁? - 我
- Strike whom? - Me.
那他为什么要杀玛丽古德?
So why would he kill Marigold?
这是场猫鼠游戏
It's a game,of cat and mouse.
他知道普璐登斯・斯坦利是我姨妈
He knew Prudence Stanley was my aunt.
社会版整版都报道着盖伊的婚事
It's been all over the society pages with Guy's engagement.
福尔已经死了 芙莱妮
Foyle's dead,Phryne.
可是亚瑟说和带走詹妮的是一个人
But Arthur said it was the same man who took Janey.
他在警局嫌犯录上指认出他了!
He identified him in a police line-up!
恕我直言 你堂弟没有能力
With all due respect,your cousin can't pick the difference
辨别现实与童话
between fairytales and reality.
那他怎么想起福尔了?
Why connect it with Foyle?
玛丽古德的死让他想起詹妮的死
Marigold's death reminded him of Janey's
不管看见谁 他都以为是同一个凶手
and whoever he saw,he decided it was the same bogeyman.
那个伐木工
The woodcutter.
如果不是默多克・福伊尔 那又是谁?
If it wasn't Murdoch Foyle,who was it?
管家看到玛丽古德走之前和一个人在一起
The housekeeper saw Marigold with someone before she left.
谁?
Who?
管家正要乘火车回墨尔本
She's on her way back to Melbourne by train,
多亏维多利亚警方
compliments of the Victorian Police Force,
她会亲自告诉我们
to tell us in person.
给你的邀请函
Your invitation.
作为我的同伴 参加盖伊和伊莎贝拉的派对
To Guy and Isabella's party. As my partner.
费雪小姐 我真的不想...
Oh,Miss Fisher,I really don't think...
你还有凶案要查
You still have a murder case to solve
还有什么的方法
and what better way to gather information
比跻身群众更好呢?
than to mingle with the crowd?
而且 我需要你提醒我
Besides,I need you to remind me
不要害怕心里阴影
not to be afraid of shadows.
小姐 你真的认为福尔先生还活着吗?
Do you really think Mr Foyle is still alive,Miss?
也许他只是在我心里阴魂不散
Perhaps he's just haunting me,
桃乐西 杰克说得对
Dot. Jack's right.
说不通啊
It's not logical.
希望洗个热水澡能让我清醒清醒
Let's hope a hot bath will bring me to my senses.
我想让你再去查查 关于默多克・福伊尔的事
I want you to check again. On Murdoch Foyle.
桃乐西 你怎么也说这个
Not you too,Dottie.
他曾试图越狱 但是计划未遂
He tried to escape from prison,the plan went wrong
他最后被烧死了
and he was cremated instead.
那就不能再调查他了么
So there's no way of digging him up to check.
这不是很可疑吗?
Isn't that suspicious?
这是他妈妈的意愿
It's what his mother wanted.
- 是她要求的 - 把她名字告诉我
- It was at her request. - Then get me her name.
你的口气和费雪小姐一样
You sound just like Miss Fisher.
你们就不能相信记录吗?
Why can't you trust the records?
因为记录可以伪造
Because records can be falsified.
我陪伴芙莱妮小姐这么久以来
And in all the time I've been Miss Phryne's companion,
她的直觉从来就没错过
her instincts have never been wrong.
虽然如此 但凡事都有第一次
Yes,well,there's always a first.
你到底是帮还是不帮?
So does that mean you're going to help me or not?
我看看有什么我能帮上的
I'll see what I can do.
不 我才不穿那个
No,I'm not wearing that.
你需要进入角色
You need to look the part.
什么角色? 企鹅先生? 还是血腥熊猫?
And what part's that? Part penguin,part panda bloody bear?
你在这呢 芙莱妮!
Ah! There you are,Phryne.
你还记得要去拿法式小蛋糕吗?
Did you remember to collect the petit fours?
我拿了 就差赛斯和伯特把它们从车上卸下来
I did,if Cec and Bert would unload them from the car.
啊... 别浪费这一趟
Ah... Don't waste a trip.
把玛丽古德的东西捎给他爸
You can take Marigold's things back to her father.
- 什么东西? - 别管它了
- What things? - Don't worry about it.
警察都调查过了 跟我来 小伙子们
The police have finished with them. Follow me,young men.
我们干嘛要接受这个工作?
Why did we agree to this job?
只是黄昏前这会
It's only for the early part of the evening.
而且我需要你盯着简
And I need you to keep an eye on Jane.
别管那个包了 赛斯 我自己拿
Leave the bag,Cec. I'll deliver it myself.
费雪小姐 打扰了 小姐 你最好快点过来
Miss Fisher! Excuse me,Miss. You'd better come quick.
巴特勒先生!
Mr Butler!
你吃了多少乳糖
How much fudge did you eat?
一块 两块... 系鞋带
One,two... Buckle my shoe.
- 两块? - 三块... 四块!
- Two pieces? - Three... Four!
四块?!
Four pieces?!
他竟然还能站着
And he's still standing.
那个乳糖有什么问题吗?
What is wrong with the fudge?
里面加了麻药
It's laced with hash.
你是说大麻?
Do you mean hashish?
以我对盖伊的了解 应该是高质量的大麻
Highest quality,if I know Guy.
谢谢
Thank you.
长官 特露布尼太太的火车四点到达
Mrs Truebody's train arrives at four,sir.
噢 如果我赶不回来
Well,if I'm not back by then,
就由你给她做一下笔录吧
you'll have to interview her yourself.
呃 她应该是个重要证人吧 长官
Uh,but I thought she had important evidence,sir?
希望如此 科林斯
I hope she does,Collins.
但我不知道庭审何时结束
But I'm not sure when I'll be released from court
我相信你能处理好
and I have faith in your abilities.
谢谢警官 您在哪个法庭?
Thank you,sir. Ah,which court house is it?
以防我有急事找您
Just in case I need to find you.
联邦行政司法法庭
The Federal Magistrate's.
那不是专门处理离婚案件的吗 警官?
That's the Divorce Court,isn't it,sir?
对
I believe so.
祝您好运 长官
Well,good luck,sir.
- 噢 怎么晕乎乎的 - 让他躺下 伯特
- Oh,I do feel queer. - Lie him down somewhere,Bert.
- 睡一觉就好了 - 好主意
- Sleep's the best thing. - Good idea.
清醒之前有你受的
Going to get a lot worse before it gets better.
巴特勒先生怎么了?
What's wrong with Mr Butler?
他吃了盖伊的乳糖
He took a liking to Guy's fudge.
别再问了 亲爱的桃乐西 你会很震惊的
Don't press me,Dot dear. You would be very shocked.
告诉我 对于这个你怎么看
Now tell me,what do you make of these?
好漂亮啊 小姐 梭织花边真美
Why,they're lovely,Miss. Such beautiful silk tatting.
是法国的吗?
Are they French?
我也怀疑 但不是我的
I suspect so. They're not mine.
几乎看不到针脚
The stitching is practically invisible.
肯定花了不少钱
They must have cost a penny.
对玛丽古德・布朗来说的确不少
Too many pennies for Marigold Brown.
肯定是个礼物 而且很可能是男朋友送的
They must have been a present. Possibly from a gentleman friend.
这个礼物的确不太适当
That's a very inappropriate sort of present.
一位富有的男朋友
A rich gentleman friend
做出如此不适当的举动
given to inappropriate behaviour.
- 你首先想到谁了? - 盖伊先生
- Who springs immediately to mind? -Mr Guy.
探长去哪儿了?
So where's the Inspector?
他肯定告诉你他什么时候回来的吧?
Surely,he gave you some indication of when he'd return?
- 他自己也不清楚 - 没关系
- He didn't seem to know. - Never mind.
回普璐登斯姨妈家的路上 我路过法庭
I'm heading past the court house on my way back to Aunt Prudence's.
- 到时候去找他 - 不不 小姐...
- I can catch him there. - No,no,Miss,I...
他应该不希望有别人去打扰他
don't think he would like that very much.
为什么?
Why not?
他...有些私事要处理
Ah,he... I think it might be a personal matter.
私事?
Personal?
他没抢银行吧?
He hasn't robbed a bank,has he?
他...他只是...
He... He's...
特露布尼夫人等着我给她沏茶呢
Mrs Truebody is waiting for her tea.
那个女管家? 她能提供什么证据吗?
THE housekeeper? Has she been helpful?
她说她...
She says she has...
她要提供一些信息 但是她不太方便说
She says she has information but she says it's delicate
她需要跟一个女警官说
and she's demanding to speak to a lady police officer.
整个国家才四个女警官
There are only four of them in the state!
我已经解释过了
I tried to explain.
也许女调查员
Perhaps a lady investigator
也能凑合一下?
would do?
我已经对那家尽心尽力了 费雪小姐
I've done my best for that household,Miss Fisher.
我知道斯坦利太太是个难缠的雇主
I know Mrs Stanley can be a demanding employer
所以我一直谨言慎行
but I have exacting standards myself.
- 你并非因为斯坦利太太才离开? - 是
- So that's not why you left? - No.
我离开的前一晚发生了一件意外
There was an unfortunate incident the night before.
我去楼上给盖伊先生的房间铺床
I went upstairs to turn down the bed in Mr Guy's room.
我敲门了 但是无人应答
I knocked but nobody answered.
然后你直接进去了?
So you went in?
哦 那个情景我不会忘记的
Oh,it's a sight I won't forget in a hurry.
多玛与蛾摩拉:罪恶之地
就像所多玛与蛾摩拉
Like Sodom and Gomorrah.
- 是盖伊和他未婚妻? - 半对半不对
- Guy and his fiance? - I'd say so.
说实话 我看不到他们的脸
But to tell the truth,I couldn't see their faces,
是两个年轻女人
the two young ladies.
还有盖伊先生
Only Mr Guy's.
我真不想跟他们呆在同一屋檐下
So I couldn't stay under the same roof after that
我也不知道怎么跟可怜的斯坦利太太说
and I didn't know how to tell poor Mrs Stanley.
蓝胡子:传说中乱娶妻妾然后杀害她们的人
看看这个吧 蓝胡子
Have a look at these,Bluebeard.
熟悉吧?
Look familiar?
你们谁给玛丽古德送一条法国内裤?
Which one of you gave Marigold French underwear?
那个蠢女人进来竟然不敲门
Stupid woman should have knocked.
- 她才16岁 - 别在这说教 芙莱妮
- She was barely 16! - Oh,don't go all moralistic on us,Phryne.
你巴不得自己也十六呢吧
You like your meat tender too.
我们三个玩得很开心
We had some perfectly lovely times,the three of us.
但盖伊却把这一切都毁了
Then Guy had to go and spoil it all.
这不是我的错
It wasn't my fault.
我去拿酒 那个小贱人一直跟着我到地下室
The little minx followed me down to the cellar when I went to get supplies.
她恳求盖伊让她跟我们一起回伦敦
She pleaded with Guy to take her back to London with us.
否则就跟大家说使我们逼她的
Even threatened to claim we'd forced her.
这个威胁可以成为你的杀人动机啊
Well,there's your motive.
她父亲才是有动机的人
Her father's the one with the motive.
他地下室看到我们了 简直尴尬极了
He found us in the cellar. It was jolly embarrassing.
是玛丽古德的血让他发了狂
It was Marigold's blood he was baying for,though.
他把她拽出去 骂她是荡妇
He dragged her off,called her a slut and a whore,
吵闹了一番
making a dickens of a row.
所以我只好送他一瓶名酒
I had to appropriate a bottle of something expensive
好让他们息事宁人
and go after them to calm things down.
所以就因为一瓶酒
So for the sake of a drink,
赫伯特就原谅了他女儿的所作所为?
Herbert was prepared to overlook his daughter's cavorting?
不 他肯定杀了她
No,he must have killed her.
所以他才勒索我帮他证明不在场
Why else would he be blackmailing me into giving him an alibi?
你既然没跟赫伯特一起 那你当时在哪儿?
So if you weren't with Herbert,what's your alibi?
我跟伊莎贝拉在图书馆一直呆到十点钟
I was with Isabella in the library until after ten.
我和花农有约
Hmm,I had an appointment with the florist.
但她不停地唠叨
She kept banging on about the symbolism
兰花和千金子藤的花语
of orchids and stephanotis
接着就听到盖伊的妈妈发现尸体后的尖叫
until Guy's mother started screaming about Marigold.
克里奥帕特拉 真是蛇蝎美人啊!
Cleopatra. Oh,what an asp!
好 芙莱妮 今晚别提
Now Phrynekins,about this Marigold business.
关于玛丽古德那件案子了 好吗?
Don't make a fracas tonight.
- 要想想我母亲的感受 - 别担心 盖伊
- Think what it will do to Mother. - Don't worry,Guy.
普璐登斯阿姨今晚已经够忙乎的了
Aunt Prudence is in for a difficult enough evening as it is.
- 我不会再雪上加霜的 - 爱死你
- I won't make it worse. - I do love you.
应该的
So you should.
- 你看起来美极了 - 谢谢 你也是
- You look perfect. - Thank you. So do you.
好 今晚只许喝柠檬汽水 不准碰乳糖
Now,only lemonade tonight and no fudge.
对了 有人给你留了张纸条
Oh,someone left a note for you.
还在楼上梳妆台
It's still upstairs on the dressing table.
我去拿 正好我要去看看亚瑟
I'll get it. I'm going to check on Arthur.
亚瑟?
Arthur?
嗨 亚瑟
Hello,Arthur.
为什么不去参加订婚派对?
Why aren't you at the party?
母亲说盖伊不喜欢我
Mother says Guy doesn't want me.
我会说服盖伊的
I can deal with Guy.
我在这儿挺好的 我可以看书
I'll be good. I'll read my book.
你会错过很多好玩的东西
You'll miss out on all the fun.
待会儿会有寻宝游戏
There's going to be a treasure hunt.
我给你带了些点心
I brought you some treats.
我不饿
Not hungry.
你也许会后悔哦
You might change your mind.
巴特勒先生还好吧?
Is Mr Butler going to be alright?
他会恢复的 只是因为吃了些乳糖
He'll be fine. It was just a reaction to some fudge.
他可能对无花果过敏
He must be allergic to figs.
关于默多克・福伊尔火化的事 有了一些进展
I found out more about Murdoch Foyle's cremation.
是他母亲格特鲁德・克拉克请求火化的
It was at the request of his mother,Mrs Gertrude Clark.
她不姓福尔?
Her name's not Foyle?
她是他的养母 我去福利院查过
She was a foster mother so I checked with Welfare
他们对她印象很深 因为她曾被控告
and they remembered her because she was charged with
虐待手下的六个孤儿
maltreating six orphans in her care...
有的挨饿 有的被打
starvation and brutality.
在监狱呆了两年半
She spent two and a half years in prison.
我已经查过她的资料
I've been through her file.
这号人我可不太想见
Well,she doesn't sound like the kind of person I'd want to meet.
你找到地址了吗?
But did you find an address?
找到了 但是没用
I did but it's no help.
克拉克夫人两周前
Mrs Clark's been listed as a missing person
被报为失踪人口
for the past fortnight.
杰克 你来啦
Jack,you made it.
- 克里奥帕特拉 尼罗河女王 - 很好
- Cleopatra,Queen of the Nile. - Very good.
我想休已经跟你说了我跟特露布尼的谈话?
I assume Hugh told you about our interview with Mrs Truebody?
- 是的 - 很好
- He did. - Good.
剩下的 我来告诉你
I can fill you in on the rest.
但是首先 你得换件衣服
But first,you need a costume.
你都不知道我怎么打算 就要极力反对?
How can you protest when you have no idea what it is I have in mind?
因为你的打算
Because nine times out of ten,
十有八九会让我很郁闷
what you have in mind gives me grief.
我这样穿没什么不好吧
There's nothing wrong with the way I'm dressed.
完美地扮演了一位警探
I'm perfectly disguised as a police detective.
你在派对上穿羊毛西装 戴领带
You won't detect much in a crowd this fast
是不会查出什么线索的 我给你准备了这件
in a blue wool suit and tie. I kept this aside for you.
是马克安东尼国王
A passable Mark Antony,
马克安东尼国王:埃及女王的丈夫
如果能偷来台球室的那把剑就更好了
if we pilfer that sword on display in the billiard room.
所以我要从世界的三根顶梁柱之一
So I'm to be the triple pillar of the world
变成妓女都能愚弄的傻瓜
transformed into a strumpet's fool?
你做扬善除恶的大英雄已经够久了
You've been at least a single pillar for far too long.
- 谁也认不出你的 - 除了你
- No-one will know who you are. - Except you.
来吧杰克 就三俗一晚上吧
Come on,Jack. Just one gaudy night.
如果你一定要我装扮罗马士兵
If you really want a Roman soldier...
那就交给我自己吧
then I'll take it from here.
- 那是什么 - 是留给我的
- What is it? - This was left for me.
是詹妮的
It was Janey's.
她消失的那天系的就是这对发带
She was wearing ribbons in her hair the day she disappeared.
- 我有另一条 - 怎么会
- I have the other one. - How?
我不知道 肯定是他
I don't understand. It must be him.
当日还有谁见到了这发带
Who else was there that day who could have found it?
除了福尔 还有别人么?
Apart from Foyle,anyone else?
警察在现场 我的父母
The police were there,obviously. My parents.
普璐登斯姑妈去接...
Aunt Prudence came to collect...
亚瑟 放下
Arthur,put that down.
亚瑟
Arthur.
别
No...
- 他走了 - 他不会伤害任何人
- He's gone! - He wouldn't hurt anyone.
我们必须找到他
We've got to find him.
狼人 他穿了狼人的衣服
The wolf. He's taken the wolf costume.
亚瑟
Arthur!
女士们先生们 寻宝游戏即将开始
Ladies and gentlemen,we are about to begin our treasure hunt!
三等奖 半箱法国香槟
Third prize,half a case of French champagne!
二等奖 一整箱法国香槟
Second prize,an entire case of French champagne!
一等奖
First prize...
和伊莎贝拉在闺房共度良宵
a night in the boudoir with Isabella!
或者和我
Or me!
或者和我俩
Or both!
女士们先生们 第一个线索
Here's your first clue,ladies and gentlemen.
香甜虽然可以复制
A rose by any other name would smell as sweet
但带你找到宝藏的玫瑰只有一朵
but only one rose will lead you to your treat.
各就各位 女士们先生们
On your marks,ladies and gentlemen.
准备好进入今晚的高潮吧
Get set for the highlight of the evening and...
出发吧
tally-ho!
细细寻找
Onward and upward!
简去哪里了
Where's Jane?
- 她刚才还在 - 简
- She was here. - Jane!
这么说 监狱按克拉克女士的要求
So the prison sent his body
把他的遗体寄给了你们
to you at Mrs Clark's request?
没错
That's right.
我不能记住每个来访者
I don't remember everyone who comes through
- 但她是个很特别的人 - 怎么说
- but she was an odd one. - In what way?
她取消了火化
She signed off on the job,
我们带她看了死者
we showed her in to view the deceased
然后就再没见过她
and then we never saw her again.
也没听到过她的消息
Haven't heard from her since either.
你确定福尔先生被火化了么
But you definitely cremated Mr Foyle?
威廉姆斯小姐是他的亲戚
Uh,Miss Williams is a relative.
抱歉小姐 我不是要冒犯你
Excuse me,Miss. Didn't mean to be rude.
我们还是照原计划火化了
Yes,we went ahead with the job.
嗯 这个给您
Well,um,there you are,then.
您还请节哀顺变
Commiserations on your bereavement.
- 简 你在哪里 - 简 你还好么
- Jane,where are you? - Jane,are you alright?
我以为这是下一个线索 但上面什么都没有
I thought this was the next clue but there's nothing on it.
- 亚瑟在哪里 - 怎么了
- Where's Arthur? - What is it?
- 你该回家了简 - 收拾好你的东西简
- Time for you to go home,Jane. - Gather your things,Jane.
我让赛斯和伯特把车开来
I'll get Cec and Bert to bring around the taxi.
我们怎么判断这是不是他的
How do we tell if that's him?
那是什么
What's that?
就是骨头碎片
Just bone probably.
不 它在发光
No,it's shiny.
像是块玻璃
It's more like glass.
克拉克女士的那张照片呢
Where's that photograph of Mrs Clark?
这里有注解
Here. This description.
生于1856年 她只有一只眼睛
'Born 1856. She had one eye,
另一只是玻璃的假眼
the other was a glass eye.'
休 这骨灰不是福尔的
Hugh,these ashes are not Foyle's.
是他母亲的
They're his mother's.
被掉包了
There's been a swap.
就在你眼皮底下 妈妈 你是什么时候...
Right under your nose,Mother! When were you...
盖伊
Guy!
这是怎么了 盖伊
Guy,what's going on?
亚瑟爱简
Arthur loves Jane!
他喜欢詹妮和玛丽古德
Yes,he adored Janey and Marigold too.
你没发现么 他才是所有人的威胁
Can't you see? He's the common thread.
快住手
Stop it!
我整个人生都被该死的亚瑟占满了
All my life it's been about poor Arthur!
我知道你不想伤害任何人
I know you didn't mean to hurt anyone.
快把他带走 关到他该去的精神病院去
Just take him away and lock him in an asylum where he belongs!
不
NO!
亚瑟 算了
Arthur,let go!
你还想怎么样
What more is it going to take,huh?
盖伊 亲爱的 回来
Guy,darling,come back!
不论发生什么 亚瑟
Whatever happened,Arthur...
都不是你的错
none of it's your fault.
你可以告诉我
You can tell me.
- 求你了 - 没关系的
- Please. - Shh,it's alright,darling.
冷静点
Be calm.
这不是我的 我不能吃糖糖
It's not mine. I'm not supposed to have sweeties.
- 你从哪里弄来的 - 是他的
- Where did you get this? - It was him.
芙莱妮小姐
Miss Phryne.
那不是他 被火化的不是他
It wasn't him. He wasn't the one who was cremated.
是他的养母
It was his foster mother.
- 桃乐西 你确定么 - 当然
- Dot,are you sure? - It's true,sir.
被火化的是格特鲁德・克拉克
It was Gertrude Clarke who entered into those flames.
那个丝带
The ribbon.
亚瑟 告诉我今晚发生的一切
Arthur,tell me everything that happened tonight.
我想去参加聚会 但是妈妈不允许
I wanted to go to the party but Mother wouldn't let me.
我出去的时候 那男人出现了
And when I went outside,the man was there.
他给了我一只糖苹果 但是拿走了我的衣服
He gave me another toffee apple but he took my costume
他还打我
and he hit me.
是之前和玛丽古德在一起的那个人么
The same man you saw with Marigold?
对 是那个伐木工人
Yes. The woodcutter.
就是他带走了詹妮
The one who took Janey away.
我的天 福尔淹死了玛丽古德
Oh,my God. Foyle drowned Marigold.
他知道我会来帮姨妈 他还在逍遥法外 杰克
He knew I'd help my aunt. And he's still out there,Jack.
我能搭一个便车么
I wonder if I could trouble you for a lift?
我的车坏了 我要去圣基尔德
My car won't start and I need to get back to St Kilda.
没问题 进来吧 我们也去那个方向
No worries,jump in. We're heading that way.
我通知了所有职工
I've let all the staff know.
至少简脱离了危险
At least Jane's out of harm's way.
门房的保安看见一个男人
The guard at the gatehouse saw a man
拿着狼人衣服进了一辆出租车
holding a wolf costume flag down a taxi.
我们错过了 是赛斯和伯特
We've just missed them. Cec and Bert!
我们开我的车 桃乐西 打电话给巴特勒先生
We'll take my car. Dot,telephone Mr Butler.
提醒他锁好所有门窗
Warn him to lock all the doors and windows
告诉他简在回去的路上
and tell him Jane's on her way.
我必须要联系到他 是急事
There has to be someone at that number. It's an emergency.
你能帮我查看一下连线么
Could you please check the line for me?
- 我们到家了么 - 继续睡你的吧
- Are we home yet? - Go back to sleep,will ya?
晚安 谢谢
Goodnight,then. Thank you.
你要去哪里
So where can we drop ya?
爱克兰街附近就可以
Anywhere near Acland Street will be fine.
爱克兰街
Acland Street.
不好意思 打扰你了
Excuse me,I'm so sorry to bother you
我把家里钥匙落在了我车里
but I appear to have left my house keys back in my car.
我能用一下电话么
Do you think I could use your telephone?
当然 请进
Of course. Come in.
- 电话在这里 - 谢谢
- The telephone's just there. - Thank you.
晚上好 请帮我接
Good evening. Could you please connect me
坎伯维尔转接站
to a number at the Camberwell Exchange?
我曾是一名大学教授
I was a professor at the university.
真的么 我也想读大学 你教什么
Really? I want to go to university. What did you teach?
我教历史 我对古代世界很有热情
History was my area. Ancient worlds are my passion.
我也是 要牛奶么
Mine too! Uh,milk?
不 谢谢
No,thank you.
让我想到了埃及艳后
Makes me think of Cleopatra.
- 泡牛奶浴 - 是
- Bathing in asses' milk. - Oh,yes.
她和一个罗马将军马克安东尼相爱了
She was in love with Marc Antony,who was a Roman general.
再说些埃及艳后的事
Tell me more about Cleopatra.
感觉好些了么 巴特勒先生
Feeling better,Mr Butler?
当然 事实上我有点饿了
Yes. In fact,I'm really rather peckish.
你是...?
You are...?
艾尔森先生的车在聚会上坏了 他是历史教授
Mr Ayrton's car broke down at the party. He teaches history.
是么 很有意思
Does he? Well,that's very interesting.
谢谢你的茶 我要走了
Thank you for the tea. I should be leaving.
我送你出去 艾尔森先生
I'll see you out,Mr Ayrton.
简 你在哪里
Jane? Where are you?
- 简 - 怎么了
- Jane! - What's wrong?
他在哪里
Where is he?
默多克・福伊尔在哪里
Where's Murdoch Foyle?
他还会回来
He'll be back.